CV / Alexey Gornostaev

👋 Hi, I'm Alexey. I'm a product manager and producer in video game space.

I co-founded a video game discovery service with an open API, that was used by Microsoft, Unity, Newzoo, Blur and Yandex. I've worked with indie games, video games media and f2p products on bringing new projects to market.

✓ Contacts

- hey@lyosha.net
- lyosha.net

Skills

- Formulating/following product vision and producing production plans
- Research: competition analysis, JTBD
- Prioritisation: defining product roadmap and scope
- Key product metrics analytics
- Leading and day to day managing small to medium dev teams
- Managing distributed workspace
- Communication: clear and conscious writing (essays, tasks, memos, wikis, issues)
- Marketing: SEO, premium and f2p video game distribution
- Technical: web tech stack

Languages

- English (C1 level)
- Russian (native)

***** Education

 A degree in computer and information technologies in economics (Moscow Aviation Institute)

Experience

Herocraft - a video game developer and publisher

Producer, Oct 2024 - Present

Bringing indie PC games to the market

RAWG - a video game discovery startup / html5 games platform

Co-founder / Product Lead, Nov 2016 - 2023

- Invented the concept and led product strategy for rawg.io (screenshots)
- Defined scope and set processes to bootstrap an MVP (announcement)
- Built a comprehensive (500K+ titles with multiple fields) auto updated database
- Designed UGC recommendation tools (46 ratings / user, 10 000 database edits per year)
 Managed launch of the public API (hundreds of users, (screenshot) used by Unity, Newzoo, Blur
- and Yandex.

 Managed the development of an SDK with manatication and site integration features for htmlF.
- Managed the development of an SDK with monetisation and site integration features for html5 game developers (dozens of launched games) for the CIS market.
- Optimized user flow and DAU conversion (example)

Rambler Games - a leading entertainment media in CIS

Product Manager, Jan 2013 - Nov 2016

- Led product at one of the leading video game media in the CIS market
- Defined product roadmap, provided input to product strategy
- Managed dev team
- Doubled MAU (high point: 5M users/month)
- Produced interactive web projects for commercial clients

Game Insight - a video game developer and publisher of mobile and social games **Project Manager**, Jan 2012 - Jan 2013

- Worked on a mobile web-based in-game marketing and support platform
- Led a team that released iOS/Android SDK and server backend services
- Integrated SDK into 18+ iOS and Android titles (millions of MAU)
- Aligned the roadmap with stakeholders (top managers, marketing team and game studios)
- Turned requests from the marketing team and game studios into detailed user stories.

Kanobu.ru - an entertainment media startup

Project Manager, Aug 2011 - Jan 2012

- Was responsible for creating a video game digital distribution service for the CIS market
- Wrote initial product requirements, defined scope
- Led the development and shipped the product on time
- Operated the storefront: managed the catalog (hundreds of titles), provided customer support

Contractor work

IM Games - imtank.com - multiplayer free to play web game **Web publisher**, Oct 2023 - Oct 2024

- Led the production and performance analysis of landing pages and ad creatives
- Traffic analytics set up and analysis (GTM, Google Analytics, MixPanel)

Gather - a video game startup focused on online competitions **Consulting**, Apr 2020 - May 2021

- Consulted on product development a US-based startup that was building an online tournaments platform
- Produced product requirements for a proof of concept version
- Developed product roadmap and user acquisition strategy
- Developed efficient solutions (example) for UX flows